Ioryogi-san, it’s autumn!
It smells like autumn!
Smells like autumn?
What do you mean?
It’s a little smoky and sunny,
and it makes your chest feel a
little refreshed, or a little tight…
It’s a smell that makes you feel all nostalgic.
You don’t have your memories, but
you remember the smell of autumn?
Ioryogi-san.
What?
What’s that?
That’s amazing.
That’s the first time I’ve ever
seen such a great ginkgo tree.
It really is autumn, Ioryogi-san.
What’s wrong?
You don’t look very happy.
Hey, Kobato.
Yes?
Look at this. Do you know what this means?
Um, when it’s autumn, all the leaves dress up and do a wind dance…
What the hell kind of fantasy story do you think this is?!
Kobato! What do you wish for?
Um…
Don’t tell me you forgot!
There’s a place I want to go to!
And what do you have to do for that wish to be granted?
Um…
I have to gather confetti.
What do you have to do to gather confetti?
I have to heal broken hearts!
How long do you have?
I have until the end of the four seasons.
How many seasons do you have left?
Two.
How many do you have?
Um…
About this many…
Kobato.
Yes?
You know where you want to go, right?
Yes.
I see.
Be careful! You’ll lose your hat!
Yes…
For crying out loud.
Good morning!
Fine then! Toshihiko-kun, I hate you!
Wh-What’s wrong? You can’t
tell someone you hate them!
Yuzuru-kun and Toshihiko-kun are
fighting over wooden building blocks.
My train won’t work unless I have triangles,
but Toshihiko-kun’s using two of them!
That’s because you need two triangles to make a square.
There aren’t any more square blocks?
Yeah.
Then, let’s all make something big! Like a castle or…
I don’t want to anymore!
If you won’t use them nicely, then I won’t let you use them anymore.
Fine then!
They’re all just boring toys anyway.
Yeah. They’re old and dirty.
You might as well throw them out.
Fujimoto-san, you mustn’t!
Kiyokazu-sensei, don’t be angry!
Hey!
Hey, Kobato!
Huh? Ioryogi-san?
I thought I heard Ioryogi-san’s
voice, but Ioryogi-san’s not here.
Ioryogi-san?
Are you an idiot?!
This is no time to be moping around!
Do you think you can gather confetti like that?
That’s true, but…
Kobato-chan…
Fujimoto-kun just left for his part-time job, but did something happen?
It’s unusual for him to leave without saying goodbye. What happened?
Um…
What is it?
I see.
So that’s what happened.
Fujimoto-san didn’t get angry, but he looked so sad.
I didn’t realize that…
It’s not your fault, Kobato-chan. Or Fujimoto-kun’s.
The children put up with a lot.
I’d like to give them new toys and provide them with more, but…
Toys…
Oh! I know a good place for toys!
A good place?
Hey, where are we going?
Someplace fun!
Amazing!
It’s a big tree!
We’re going to gather fallen leaves today!
Then we’ll bring them back
and make pictures out of them!
Pictures?
Fallen leaves have all sorts of colors and shapes, right?
What kind of picture can you make?
I’m going to get some!
Me too!
Sayaka-sensei, look! It’s a pretty leaf!
My.
This is for you, Sayaka-sensei.
Kobato-chan, here!
I can have this?
Sorry.
Um, about the wood blocks…
Can you promise to use them nicely?
Yeah.
We’ll use them nicely.
And also…
There’s something you need to say after a fight, right?
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
And don’t forget to apologize to Fujimoto-kun too.
Okay.
We’ll get lots of leaves to give to Kiyokazu-sensei too!
That’s good, they made up.
They usually never fight…
I guess the anxiety of the adults really affects them.
No! Sayaka-sensei, a smile suits you much better!
Thank you.
A sad face will never find happiness, right?
Yes, a smile! A smile!
Amazing, it’s as if it’s burning with light.
Yes.
Somehow, it makes me feel purified and at peace.
Move back! It’s dangerous here.
Um, what’s happening?
We’re cutting down that tree tomorrow, so we’re setting up a fence today.
You’re cutting down the ginkgo tree?
Why? Why?
The neighbors are complaining about it.
They say it’s in the way, so
something needs to be done about it.
But it’s so pretty and big.
It’s too big, so the leaves get everywhere.
Well, we’ll be doing some redevelopment here too.
Now then, move along.
Ioryogi-san?
What’s redevelopment?
It’s when they destroy old things like
streets and buildings and put up new ones.
That’s redevelopment?
Yeah.
So they can’t keep the old things…
Does that mean they don’t need them?
That’s not exactly it.
It’s just that most people
would rather have newer things.
Hey, it isn’t time to go to the preschool.
I’m going to ask them.
I’m going to ask them to not cut down the ginkgo tree.
What?
Hey, wait up!
If I ask them, I’m sure…!
Kohaku-san?
Good morning, Kobato-san, Ioryogi-san.
Kohaku-san, were you worried about the ginkgo tree too?
Redevelopment is so harsh on old things!
Is that true?
But I’ll go ask them, so it’ll be all right!
I see.
I have no idea what’s going to be “all right.”
Oh my.
This fence wasn’t here yesterday.
They’re going to be redeveloping it.
Oh. Well, they’ve always been talking about it.
It’s such a great ginkgo tree, but there’s no other choice if it’s for the good of the neighborhood.
Oh, that’s too bad.
But it’s good to hear that they’re redeveloping it.
There’s such a huge tree here.
Doesn’t a tree that big kind of creep you out?
It kind of does.
Oh no, we’re out of time!
What’s wrong, Kobato-san?
Nothing.
You’re dissatisfied, aren’t you? Since everyone says they don’t want it.
That’s not it.
Then, what is it?
I’m wondering if the ginkgo tree is lonely.
Lonely?
It’s been here for hundreds of years, watching this town.
Yet no one cares about it…
It’ll be all right, Kobato-san.
It says it isn’t lonely.
You can tell what the ginkgo tree is saying?
Yes, somewhat.
She seems like an airhead but she’s still an angel, after all.
Um, what else did the ginkgo tree say?
It’s happy because a bunch of
children came to play with it yesterday.
It says it was fun.
Is there anything else we can do?
It says “thank you.”
And also…
…“farewell.”
It’ll be all right!
I’ll ask them to not cut you down!
Looks like it’s not hoping for that.
I’ll move the ginkgo tree!
Kobato-san?
Hey, hey. What the heck do you think you’re doing?
But, but…
But if we don’t…
The ginkgo tree… The ginkgo tree will…!
I know a wisteria tree the same age as this ginkgo tree.
That wisteria tree said the
same thing as this ginkgo tree.
The same thing?
It said that the most happy thing for it,
was that it could watch over the people it loved.
Can you hear the ginkgo tree’s song?
Yes.
It’s a little sad, but it’s so gentle.
The ginkgo tree-
That was dangerous!
What were you just standing there for?
I’m sorry…
It reached its life span.
It’s hollow inside.
Sooner or later, it would’ve withered away.
It hung on for as long as it could.
Kohaku-san.
Was the ginkgo tree happy?
Happy?
Yes, I’m sure it was.
It departed this world after finally hearing your song, Kobato-san.
Ioryogi-san?
Where did this confetti come from?
Could it be from Kohaku-san? But that doesn’t seem right…
Fujimoto-san! That can’t be it either…
It could be from the ginkgo tree.
Plants are alive too.
So it wouldn’t be unusual to heal them too.
But I couldn’t save the ginkgo tree.
You sang for it.
Sang?
Didn’t Kohaku say it?
It was able to be sent off by hearing your song.
It must’ve been pretty happy to hear that.
I see.
Here, how’s this?
Fujimoto-san, do you want to join us?
Those are…
These are… wood blocks, aren’t they?
I got some of the ginkgo tree’s branches and made them.
The gingko tree?
Amazing! You’re amazing, Fujimoto-san!
It’s nothing.
Everyone, Fujimoto-san’s making more wood blocks!
Toshihiko-kun, Yuzuru-kun,
don’t you have something to say to
Fujimoto-san before you play with the blocks?
Kiyokazu-sensei, we’re sorry!
S-Sure.
That’s good. Now you’ve all made up.
Hey, hey, Kiyokazu-sensei,
come make leaf pictures with us!
No, I’m…
If you attach a gingko leaf here,
you get a Gingko-Fujimoto Alien!
Huh?